<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Publish>
  <ModId Value="144130" />
  <DisplayName Value="Hard Mode Continued" />
  <ShortDescription Value="Unofficial continuation of Hard Mode with repaired economy difficulty, building demolition costs, and terraforming costs." />
  <LongDescription>
# Hard Mode Continued
Unofficial continuation and compatibility fix of JadHajjar's Hard Mode mod.

Original project: https://github.com/JadHajjar/HardMode
Original author: JadHajjar
License: MIT

Maintained continuation source: https://github.com/Capili81/HardModeContinued

## Features
* 4 difficulty settings in the mod's options.
* Subsidies' formula is completely reworked, you get money at the start and lose subsidies the bigger your city is. You get less money, for a lower period of time the higher the difficulty setting is.
* Milestone rewards use static money values based on the difficulty setting, instead of scaling up the higher you go.
* Income and expense factors are re-balanced and are affected by the difficulty setting. This includes changes to taxation, exported electricity, water, goods, garbage fees, etc.
* Bulldozing a building costs money based on evicted residents, land value, and building size. Costs are shown in the bulldozer tooltip and subtracted immediately when a building is demolished.
* Terraforming costs money when terrain height is changed. Costs are based on the actual height difference and scale with the selected difficulty.

## Difficulty details
The mod first rebalances individual income and expense categories, then applies the selected difficulty.

* Easy: income receives the strongest bonus, expenses are reduced to 85%, milestone rewards are 125,000 or 250,000 on every fourth milestone, building demolition costs are divided by 6, and terraforming uses the lowest cost factor.
* Medium: income receives a medium bonus, expenses are reduced to 90%, milestone rewards are 100,000 or 200,000 on every fourth milestone, building demolition costs are divided by 4, and terraforming costs use a medium factor.
* Hard: income receives only a small bonus, expenses use the full rebalanced value, milestone rewards are 50,000 or 100,000 on every fourth milestone, building demolition costs are divided by 2.5, and terraforming costs use a high factor.
* Good Luck: income receives no difficulty bonus, expenses are increased to 110%, regular milestone rewards are removed, building demolition costs are charged at full value, and terraforming uses the highest cost factor.
* Final milestone: milestone 20 still grants 1,000,000 on all difficulties.

## Current limitations
* Road, path, rail, pipe, cable, and other network demolitions do not currently charge demolition costs.
* The public options are intentionally kept simple while compatibility with current game versions is tested.

## Compatibility
* Tested on Cities: Skylines II 1.6.0f1.
* Do not use together with the original Hard Mode mod.
* This continuation is intended to replace the original Hard Mode mod.
* May conflict with other economy overhaul mods.

## Planned Features
There are no immediate promises for new features. Road/network demolition costs may be considered later if they can be implemented reliably.
	  
</LongDescription>
  <Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshot_01.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshot_02.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshot_03.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshot_04.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshot_05.png" />
  <Tag Value="Code Mod" />
  <ModVersion Value="1.2.6" />
  <GameVersion Value="1.6.*" />
  <AccessLevel Value="Public" />
  <ChangeLog>
# v1.2.6
## Terraforming costs
* Added terraforming costs when terrain height is changed with the terrain tool.
* Terraforming costs scale with the selected Economy Difficulty: Easy x1, Medium x2, Hard x3, Good Luck x4.
* Added an option to enable or disable terraforming costs.
</ChangeLog>
  <ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/hard-mode-continued-bug-reports.1926592/" />
  <ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/Capili81/HardModeContinued" />
</Publish>
